<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random on Today I learned</title>
    <link>/tags/random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random on Today I learned</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 15:38:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL</title>
      <link>/post/til/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 15:38:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/til/</guid>
      <description>Can&amp;rsquo;t believe I am starting this post well after the blog which is name TIL
 Hypermedia As The Engine Of Application State (HATEOAS)  A client interacts with a network application whose application servers provide information dynamically through hypermedia
 Example GET /accounts/12345 HTTP/1.1 Host: bank.example.com Accept: application/xml ...  The response is:
Content-Type: application/xml Content-Length: ... &amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34;?&amp;gt; &amp;lt;account&amp;gt; &amp;lt;account_number&amp;gt;12345&amp;lt;/account_number&amp;gt; &amp;lt;balance currency=&amp;#34;usd&amp;#34;&amp;gt;100.00&amp;lt;/balance&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;deposit&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;https://bank.example.com/accounts/12345/deposit&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;withdraw&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;https://bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Setup with Nginx, PHP, MongoDB, Django and Python</title>
      <link>/post/server-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 21:20:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/server-setup/</guid>
      <description>Creating a sudo user adduser username usermod -aG sudo username sudo - username  Install nginx  sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install nginx  Adjusting firewalls sudo ufw app list will give a list of nginx app profiles
 Nginx Full: This profile opens both port 80 (normal, unencrypted web traffic) and port 443 (TLS/SSL encrypted traffic) Nginx HTTP: This profile opens only port 80 (normal, unencrypted web traffic) Nginx HTTPS: This profile opens only port 443 (TLS/SSL encrypted traffic)  Enable Full for 80 and 443</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Summarization</title>
      <link>/post/text-summarization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 12:35:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/text-summarization/</guid>
      <description>Source
The process for summarization a paragraph
 So, keep working. Keep striving. Never give up. Fall down seven times, get up eight. Ease is a greater threat to progress than hardship. Ease is a greater threat to progress than hardship. So, keep moving, keep growing, keep learning. See you at work.
 Paragraph to sentences So, keep working Keep striving Never give up Fall down seven times, get up eight Ease is a greater threat to progress than hardship Ease is a greater threat to progress than hardship So, keep moving, keep growing, keep learning See you at work  Text Preprocessing Removing special characters,stop words and numbers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Happens When</title>
      <link>/post/what-happens-when/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:43:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/what-happens-when/</guid>
      <description>This is a short version of the question what happens when you enter google.com in your browser.  credit When you type &amp;ldquo;G&amp;rdquo;  The browser receives the event and the auto-complete functions kick in. Various suggestions will be presented to you in the dropbox below the URL bar   When you press &amp;ldquo;Enter&amp;rdquo;  Small amount of current to flow into the logic circuitry of the keyboard, which scans the state of each key switch, debounces the electrical noise of the rapid intermittent closure of the switch, and converts it to a keycode integer, in this case 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When I Did</title>
      <link>/post/when-i-did/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 21:20:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/when-i-did/</guid>
      <description>Trifle hacks I did Bash commands for lazying Lazy git  For easy git add, commit and push
function gitl() { git add . git commit -a -m &amp;quot;$*&amp;quot; git push origin master }   PHP switches  Switching between PHP versions
 function on7() { sudo a2dismod php5.6 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo a2enmod php7.1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo service apache2 restart }  function on5() { sudo a2dismod php7.1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo a2enmod php5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx Server Block</title>
      <link>/post/nginx-server-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:31:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nginx-server-block/</guid>
      <description>Nginx This is just a copy of the server configuration of my EC2 instance which contains a Django, PHP and a static applications.
The Django application is served by the help of Uwsgi and Nginx courtesy of this article To quote the article,
 This will serve as an interface to our applications which will translate client requests using HTTP to Python calls that our application can process. We will then set up Nginx in front of uWSGI to take advantage of its high performance connection handling mechanisms and its easy-to-implement security features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidbits</title>
      <link>/post/tidbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidbits/</guid>
      <description>Make command  The make command accepts targets as command line arguments. These targets are usually specified in a file named &amp;lsquo;Makefile&amp;rsquo;, which also contains the associated action corresponding to the targets.
 Splat operator This feature allows you to capture a variable number of arguments to a function, combined with &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; arguments passed in if you like. It&amp;rsquo;s easiest to see with an example:
 function concatenate($transform, ...$strings) { $string = &#39;&#39;; foreach($strings as $piece) { $string .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>